(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T21:18:00.613414",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
やんないじゃないできないんだとや
It's not that I won't do it, I can't, nya!
ダダダダ天使
Dadadada Angel!
あー近頃巷で噂のダメ天使
Ah, lately rumor has it I'm a useless angel,
ダメなところはもう天使のパワーでおぎなっていくのだ予定さ
but I'll make up for my flaws with angel power! That's the plan!
ねぇ足りないのもっともっとあなたに気にしてほしい
Hey, if it's still not enough, I want you to pay even more attention to me,
だけど注目されすぎたらビビるディスコミュ系
though if I get too much attention, my social anxiety kicks in!
天使のリングの点滅はきれかかってるけど
My angel ring is flickering and about to die,
見方を変えればこれもアイデンティティさ
but look at it another way, that's just my identity!
なんて強がりさ本当は曖昧な感情もあなたと探したいの
That's just a bluff. Really, I want to search for these vague feelings with you.
ねぇ
Hey,
ねぇダメダメダメダメなあたしを
Hey, love me, this useless,
もっと！愛してね
useless, useless me even more!
大概のシャンダ人気者じゃん！
Everyone loves a chaotic underdog!
天使ですがドキドキドキドキをあげるよ
I'm an angel, so I'll give you heart-pounding thrills!
もっと！あなたには
More! For you,
yes!ちゃんと見ていてくれるなら
yes! If you'll watch over me properly,
エンジェル！やるよ多分
Angel! I'll do it, probably!
はい！ダダ ダダ ダメ天使は
Yes! Dada, dada, is a useless angel
ダダ ダダ ダメですか？だけどあたしはいいか？
dada, dada, useless? But is it okay if I'm me?
やんないじゃないできないんだとや
It's not that I won't do it, I can't, nya!
テストで良い点取りたいでも頭が
I want to get good grades on tests, but my head
ちっとも追いつかない日曜日だって
just won't keep up, even on Sundays
早起きしたい深夜のネットゲがやめられない
I want to wake up early, but I can't stop late-night gaming.
やる気がないとかそんなんじゃないんでやる気があってもできない仕様だ
It's not that I lack motivation, it's just designed so I can't do it even when motivated!
しょーがないなって許してよエンジェルリングを頬張りながら
So bear with me while I stuff my face with angel rings!
こんな私に誰がしたんだってこんな私に私がしたのだ
Who did this to me? Well, I did it to myself, so what!
しょーがないなって許してよエンジェルリングを頬張りながら
So bear with me while I stuff my face with angel rings!
天使の羽は使ってない飛ぶの怖いから
I don't use my angel wings because flying is scary!
ねぇ だめ だめ だめ だめなあたしで
Hey, with a useless, useless, useless me,
いいですか？
Is that okay?
実際は一サイの自信もないよな
Actually, I don't have an ounce of confidence.
天使ですが
Even though I'm an angel,
ぐる ぐる ぐる ぐる ぐる回る頭の中では
In my spinning, spinning, spinning head,
あなたのことばかり
It's all about you...
考えてるんだ だめ だめ だめ だめなあたしを
Thinking about you! A useless, useless me,
愛してよ もらった愛で求め合おうよ
Love me! Let's seek each other with love,
天使だから ドキ ドキ ドキ ドキをあげるよ
Because I'm an angel, I'll give you heartbeats!
あなたには もっと特別になってくれるなら やるよたぶん
If you'll become even more special, I'll do it, probably.
だってだってだってだってだめ天使は
Because, because, because a useless angel,
だってだってだってだめ実は
Because, because, because a useless truth—
なんないじゃないできないんかーい！
Wait, you can't do it?!
いやでも努力はしますとや！
But hey, I'll try my best!
みなさんどうもこんあくあー！
Hello everyone, it's Conaqua!
見えてますかー？こんばんはー！
Can you see me? Good evening!
みな と いうことで今日は来てくれてありがとうみなとあくあです！
So today, thank you for coming, I'm Minato Aqua!
すごいコメントが！
That's an amazing comment!
と いうことで一曲目ねえもうねあの序盤からダダダダ天使歌っていただいたんですけども、ちょっとねまだまだね今日はね歌っていくのでみんな楽しんでてくれると嬉しいです！
We started with "Dadadada Tenshi", and we'll keep singing!
そして最後にこちらねみなとあくあ重大発表とあるように最後に重大な発表もございますのでお楽しみにー！
And there will be a major announcement at the end, so look forward to it!
あれ？なんか動いてる！
Huh? Something's moving!
あれ？なんだこいつ！
Huh? What is this guy?
なんか最近いつも3Dのときは常連になっている気がする。猫！猫がいる！
Lately it feels like a regular in 3D. A cat! There's a cat!
猫も私のライブ応援しに来てくれたの？
Did the cat come to cheer for my live concert too?
猫じゃん！あすごいすごい飛び跳ねてる！あら！猫！
It's a cat! Ah, it's jumping around so much! Oh my, a cat!
あとなんだかもうさレギュラー入りしてんじゃん。どういうこと？
And it's basically a regular cast member now. What's that about?
どうしちゃったんだよ！え？えちょっとどこ行くの？ちゅちゅちゅちゅ何何何？
What happened to you?! Huh? Where are you going? Chu chu, what is it?
猫ちゃんちょっと！えどこ行ったんだよ？猫ちゃん！
Kitty, wait! Huh, where did it go? Kitty!
ちょっと！猫！猫！はあ、ちょっと
Wait! Cat! Cat! Phew, wait—
ここどこ？あれなんかいつの間にか知らないところにきている。知らない天井がある。
Where is this? I've ended up somewhere unfamiliar. An unknown ceiling.
ちょっと待って猫を追いかけてたらなんか私どこだここ？わかんない私は誰？ここはどこ？
Wait, after chasing the cat, where am I? Who am I? Where is this?
ちょっとみんなのいるステージに早く戻らないと。
I have to hurry back to the stage where everyone is.
う、頭が！なのに帰り道が思い出せない！私、どうしたらいいの！？
Ugh, my head! But I can't remember the way back! What should I do?!
おや？わあ！こんなところに何か怪しげな、いかにも怪しげな瓶がある！
Oh? Wow! There's some suspicious bottle in a place like this!
え？なんだこれ？いかにも怪しげな、すごくテラテラに見えなくもない、瓶が
Huh? What's this? A really suspicious bottle that looks kind of shiny...
あれ？
Huh?
なんだろこれ？
What's this?
瓶の中身を飲めば帰り道が分かるはず。
If I drink what's in the bottle, I should know the way back.
なんだこれ？脱出ゲーム始まったもしかして。
What is this? Did an escape game start?
やばいどうしようみんな！
Oh no, what should I do everyone!
デスゲームが始まる！まずい！
A death game is starting! This is bad!
全部で3つの謎解きに挑戦しますと。
It says we will take on three riddles in total.
お、777？
Oh, 777?
そして3つめの謎を解くことで箱を開けて瓶の中身を飲める。
And by solving the third riddle, open the box and drink the contents.
そして、なんと途中でゲストからヒントがもらえる。
And amazingly, we can get hints from guests along the way.
やばいなんか脱出ゲーム始まっちゃったんだけど。
Oh no, an escape game actually started.
マジか。
Seriously.
どんな問題が出るの一旦ね置いといてこれまだ使えないみたいだから。
What kind of questions will come up? Let's leave that aside for now since we can't use it yet.
何の問題が出るんだろう。
I wonder what kind of questions will appear.
なんでもかかってこいよ！謎解きでしょ？
Bring it on! It's just a riddle, right?
IQ5000私に任せたら楽勝よ！
If you leave IQ 5000 to me, it's a piece of cake!
お、これか？謎が
Oh, is this it? The riddle...
お、あ、来た！お急ぎに来るな。
Oh, ah, it came! It comes in a hurry.
はい、この人物に次の謎を伝えておく。
Yes, convey the next riddle to this person.
3、4、5、6、7、8、9、10、11、12、13、1、2
3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 1, 2
誰に声をかける？声をかけられるのは1人だけ。
Who do you call out to? Only one person can be called out to.
え？どういうこと？おじいちゃんと、お、なんだこれお金持ち？お金持ち、マッチョ、メガネの人。
Eh? What does that mean? An old man and... oh, what is this, a rich person? Rich person, muscular guy, glasses person.
え？どういうこと？え？え？やばい。
Eh? What does that mean? Eh? Eh? Oh no.
どういうこと？
What does that mean?
3からの4からの5からの6...
From 3 to 4 to 5 to 6...
なんかさこれさ、3がさ4って喋ってるみたいだね。違うか。違うかこれ。違うね、言ってる意味わかんない人の方がほとんどだよね。
It's like 3 is talking to 4. Is that wrong? Is that wrong? No, most people wouldn't understand what it means.
え、どういうことだ？3からの4からの…え？
Eh, what does that mean? From 3 to 4 to... eh?
なんだろう？なんで1じゃないんだろう？なんで13の後がこれ1なの？
Why is it not 1? Why is 13 followed by 1?
え、どういうことだ？13の後が1で2で
Eh, what does that mean? 13 followed by 1, 2...
だから3が1番ちっちゃいってことだよね。3が1番ちっちゃくてで、2が1番大きいの？
So 3 is the smallest. 3 is the smallest and 2 is the largest?
なんと？おじいちゃん声をかけれる。
What? Old man, you can call out to him.
おじいちゃん、もしもしおじいちゃん。もしもし、お金持ちの人？もしもし、マッチョ？もしもし…え、どういうことだ？
Grandpa, hello grandpa. Hello, rich person? Hello, muscular guy? Hello... eh, what does that mean?
3が小さい、4、2が…
3 is small, 4, 2 is...
わかっちゃった気がする！
I feel like I figured it out!
わかっちゃった気がするこれ！
I feel like I figured it out, this!
え？3が大きくて…あ、待って間違った間違った。3が小さくて2が大きいんでしょ？
Eh? 3 is big... Ah wait, wrong wrong. 3 is small and 2 is big, right?
で、この矢印の中…
And inside this arrow...
答えは2個目の「お金持ち」！つまり、これ大富豪でしょ！トランプだこれ！
The answer is the second one, rich person! In other words, this is daifugo! It's cards!
正解？で、あった！
Correct? Is it right? It was!
あれ、楽勝かマジで。え？私賢い？
Huh, is it really a piece of cake? Eh? Am I smart?
IQ5000！あれ、私賢いかももしして。
IQ 5000! Huh, maybe I'm smart.
あらりゃ！これ簡単ならすぐ脱出ちゃうぞ、これ。もう開始10分で脱出じゃんべえこれ！ええ！？
Oh my! If it's this easy, I'll escape right away. Escape in 10 minutes, right here! Eh!?
じゃ、ちょっと次行くか。ちょっと早く帰りたいよ。ライブしなきゃいけないんだよ。
Well, shall we go to the next one? I want to go home quickly. I have to do a live stream.
アイドルだからさ。
Because I'm an idol.
早く…
Quickly...
早く帰らせろ！こっから…この、なんかキノコ出てきた。このキノコを食べれば、次の謎が現れる。ただし、食べられるのは1つだけ。他は毒がある。
Let me go home quickly! From here... this, some mushroom appeared. If you eat this mushroom, the next riddle will appear. However, you can only eat one. The others are poisonous.
いかにも全部毒がありそうなお色してる。茶色しかなんか食べられそうな色なくない？紫とか絶対ヤバイでしょ。え、どういうこと？
They all look like poisonous colors. Aren't brown the only edible colors? Purple is definitely dangerous. Eh, what does that mean?
茶色、紫、オレンジ、緑。青足す黄色は×。青足す赤は×。
Brown, purple, orange, green. Blue plus yellow is X. Blue plus red is X.
赤足す黒は×。黄色足す赤は○。
Red plus black is X. Yellow plus red is O.
え、どういうことだ？なんだこれ。バツバツ、マルバツ、色…ちょっと、ゲスト呼んでみる。
Eh, what does that mean? What is this? X X, O X, color... Wait, let's try calling a guest.
あなたがさ、1発目、1個目のさ、問題さ、簡単にクリアしちゃったからさ、
Since you cleared the first puzzle so easily,
ちょっとさ、ゲストの出番なくなっちゃうかもしれないから、ちょっとゲスト呼んでみる。
your guest appearance might be gone, so let's call a guest!
ゲストの…ちょ、ライフライン！プリーズ！プリーズ！
Guest... lifeline, please! Please!
ゲストの人、ゲストのさ…助、助、あれ？
Mr. Guest, guest... help, help, huh?
Aqua様、あたし、賢いIQ5000とか言ってませんでしたっけ？あれ？
Aqua-sama, didn't you say you were smart with an IQ of 5000? Huh?
あれ？その声は、その声は…ちょこちゃん？
Huh? That voice is... Choco-chan?
はーい、ホロライブ2期生、Aquaの身代わり保険、癒やしちょこです！ということでね、ちょっと待ってよ！
Hi~, Hololive 2nd Gen, Aqua's scapegoat insurance, Healing Choco here! So wait a minute!
あれ？何でホロライブヘルプって言われて呼ばれてきたんだけど、あれ？
Huh? Why was I called here saying Hololive Help? Huh?
天才のAqua様様に、あれ？これ、ヒント要ります？
To genius Aqua-sama? Huh? Do you need a hint for this?
え？いる、い…ね？
Eh? Do I... you know?
一応言ってみたよ。あたし分かんないの。
I just said it just in case. I don't get it.
あ、Aqua様、あたし…分かる、もうちょっと考えれば分かるけど。
Ah, Aqua-sama, I... I understand, if I think a bit more I'll get it.
でも、だってさ、もう呼、出番なくなっちゃうかもしれないから呼んであげたんだよ。
But hey, I thought your turn might be gone so I called you!
あ、本当に天才のAqua様に？
Ah, really, to the genius Aqua-sama?
やばい、完全にバカにされてる。
Oh no, I'm completely being made a fool of.
ちょこちゃん、この問題分かんの？
Choco-chan, do you understand this puzzle?
いや、もうちょこは余裕ですよ、こういうのは。
Well, Choco-chan finds this kind of thing a breeze.
え、任せてほしい。
Eh, leave it to me.
ヒントは、ヒント、ヒント、1個だけ、1個、1個ヒント、1個、1個。
Hints, hint, hint, just one hint, one, one hint, one, one!
え、Aqua様、よく見てみて。はい、よく見た。
Eh, Aqua-sama, take a close look. Yes, I looked closely.
よく見たら、なんか…丸に色がついちゃいませんか？
If you look closely, isn't there... color on the circles?
はい、色ついてます。青とか赤とかついてます。レッド、ブルー、イエロー、イエロー、ブルー、イエロー、イエロー、ブルー。
Yes, they have colors. Blue, red, etc. Red, blue, yellow, yellow, blue, yellow, yellow, blue...
なんか、その、色の真ん中にプラスってついてるから、それ混ぜたら何色になるんでしょうね？
It has a plus in the middle of those colors, so I wonder what color they turn into if you mix them?
え、じゃあ、え、じゃあ最初の青色と黄色を混ぜると何色ですか？
Eh, then, eh, then what color do you get when you mix the first blue and yellow?
青と黄色は…わ、わかんない。
Blue and yellow is... I, I don't know.
おい！み、緑、緑、緑、緑！あ、よかった、よかった！緑色ね？うん、うん。
Hey! Gr-, green, green, green, green! Ah, good, good! Green, right? Yeah, yeah.
あ、そういうことか！あ、そういうことか！
Ah, that's what it means! Ah, that's what it is!
じゃあ、赤と黒は？赤と黒。
Then, red and black? Red and black.
は、黒。
Is, black.
お、おけ、おけ。
O-ok, ok.
じゃあ、青足す赤は？紫！
Then, blue plus red? Purple!
紫。あ、ちなみに、あの、赤足す黒、おれ今黒って言ったかもしれなくて。
Purple. Ah, by the way, um, red plus black, I might have just said black.
え、茶色、茶色、茶色、茶色！茶色、茶色、茶色！な、なるほどな！
Eh, brown, brown, brown, brown! Brown, brown, brown! I see!
あ、そういうことね！はいはいはいはい！じゃあ、黒足す赤は？オレンジ！
Ah, that's what it is! Yes yes yes yes! Then, black plus red? Orange!
正解です！やったあ、オレンジか！
Correct! Yay, orange!
いや、さすがIQ5000だぜ！
Man, as expected of an IQ of 5000!
ね、わかってたんだよね。みんなにもね、やっぱね、ちゃんとね、そうそう、番組のことを考えてね、ちゃんとね、考えて、おふざけしてあげたんだよ。
See, I knew it. For everyone, you know, thinking about the show, I properly messed around for you guys.
あ、なるほどね！はいはい！いや、まさかちょこの学力テストのテストの点が低くても、おバカって言われても、毎回でも、
Ah, I see! Yes yes! No way, even if Choco's academic test scores are low, even if I'm called an idiot every time,
いや、お前だってやばいじゃん、マジでもう！
Man, you're just as bad, seriously!
え、次、ごめん、次。次。ちょこちゃん、じゃあ、このままいてよ。うん。
Eh, next, sorry, next. Next. Choco-chan, stay like this. Yeah.
あ、ちょこ、いたほうがいい？ちょこ、いてよ。
Ah, should Choco stay? Choco, stay.
しょうがないな、Aqua様がいてほしいっていうなら、ちょこ、いっちゃおうかな。
Can't be helped, if Aqua-sama wants me to stay, Choco will stay.
全然大丈夫、じゃあ大丈夫。
Totally fine, then it's fine.
そんなこと言わないでよ、Aqua様！せっかく、せっかく真面目に…
Don't say things like that, Aqua-sama! After working hard...
え、じゃあ、次、次、次、次。
Eh, then, next, next, next, next.
ちょこちゃんの問題、お願いします！
Choco-chan's puzzle, please!
うん、ちょこちゃんここにいるんだもんね。え、もう、Aqua様がいてほしいって可愛いことお願いしたから…
Yeah, Choco-chan is right here. Eh, since Aqua-sama made such a cute request wanting me here...
現れたの？一緒に迷いになったの？もしかして、ちょこちゃんも。
Did you appear? Did you get lost together, Choco-chan?
いや、ちょこね、ずっとここに閉じ込められてるんだもんね。
No, Choco has been locked in here the whole time.
ちょっと今日、なんかね…出れなくて…
Today, somehow... I couldn't get out...
一緒に出ようね！一緒に連れてってくださいね、Aqua様！
Let's get out together! Please take me with you, Aqua-sama!
なんだこれ？2と1が秘密を知っている。784。
What is this? 2 and 1 know the secret. 784.
これ、レバーがある。え、これどういうこと？レバーを引くってこと？
This has levers. Eh, what does this mean? Pulling the levers?
そう、これ、レバーを…押すと、何なのこれ？この絵が変わります。
Yes, this, if you press the levers... what is this? This picture changes.
え、でも、今んとこ2匹と1人だけどね。
Eh, but right now there are 2 animals and 1 person though.
ちょっと、レバー引いてみてもいい？本当に引いてみていいの？
Wait, can I try pulling the lever? Is it really okay to pull it?
じゃあ、えっと、ペコらちゃんの絵の書いてある下のレバーを引きます！ドダンと！
Then, um, I'll pull the lever below Pekora-chan's picture! Bam!
お願いします！
Please!
お！
Oh!
しょん、え、これさ、全部やってみたほうがいいよね？
Shon, eh, shouldn't we try all of them?
まあ、まあ、まあ、一応ね、見いといたほうがいいかも。
Well, well, well, just in case, it might be good to check.
テトちゃんのとこも引きます、はいどどん！
I'll draw from Teto-chan's spot too. Here we go, boom!
すばる？
Subaru?
1羽、1羽、1羽、1羽…
One bird, one bird, one bird...
ちょっとじゃあ、ぼたんちゃんのとこも引きます、どどん！
Let's also draw from Botan-chan's spot. Boom!
どどん！
Boom!
ええっ？お湯？
Eh? Hot water?
おっと、これは……
Oh, this is...
もし真ん中が私だったらね、一応まあこんな三角関係の出来上がりなわけだけれど、私のことを奪い合う三角……
If the center was me, we'd have this kind of love triangle fighting over me...
違うの、引き合いに出してくるのお前は！
That's not it, you're the one bringing it up!
あれ違う？あれ違う？
Wait, no? Wait, no?
うん、それはね、ちょっと取り合いになっちゃうから。
Yeah, that would cause a bit of a tug-of-war.
え、でも、もう1羽は足りない。もう1羽は足りない。
Eh, but, another bird isn't enough. Another bird isn't enough.
え、しかも動物が3匹いる、どうしよう？
Eh, plus there are 3 animals, what should we do?
え、どういうことだ？2羽と1匹、2羽…1匹…1回じゃあ元に戻してみます？
Eh, what does this mean? 2 birds and 1 beast... Shall we try putting them back once?
そうなんだ、全部。全部戻そう。一回じゃあ一番最初の元に戻しましょうか。
That's right, all of them. Let's return to the very beginning first.
すばる、お湯？
Subaru, hot water?
え？5、3、7、2羽、わ、2羽…
Eh? 5, 3, 7, 2 birds, wa, 2 birds...
2羽…
2 birds...
え？そうだよ、2羽。
Eh? That's right, 2 birds.
7、うさ、7、7…
7, rabi-, 7, 7...
ちなみになんですけど、ここに書かれてる数字が脱出の鍵となりそうですね、なんか。ねね、8。
By the way, the numbers written here seem to be the key to escaping. Nene, 8.
ねね、8。2羽と1匹が秘密を知っている。2羽…
Nene, 8. 2 birds and 1 beast know the secret. 2 birds...
2羽… 2羽？
2 birds... 2 birds?
1匹、1羽、ひき、ひき、ひき…
1 beast, 1 bird, -hiki, -hiki, -hiki...
2羽と1匹ね？うん。
2 birds and 1 beast, right? Yeah.
え、わかんない！え、わかんないの？
Eh, I don't get it! Eh, you don't get it?
え、ヒント！ヒントヒントヒント！ヒント！じゃあ。
Eh, hint! Hint, hint, hint! Hint! Then.
え？これは、数え方に
Eh? This might have a hint on how to count...
ヒントがあるかもしれないですね。うん。
There might be a hint. Yeah.
だから、ぼたんちゃんは違うんだ。ぼたんちゃん違う。
So, Botan-chan is different. Botan-chan is different.
本当に？
Really?
で、ここお湯だったよね。お湯が1匹だから、うんうんうん。お湯、すばる、ぺこらちゃん。
And, this was hot water, right? Hot water is 1 beast, yeah. Hot water, Subaru, Pekora-chan.
本当に？
Really?
え？２羽でいいの？本当に？
Eh? 2 birds is fine? Really?
ぺこらちゃんがうさぎだから、うん。うさぎって1羽じゃない？
Pekora-chan is a rabbit, so yeah. Isn't a rabbit counted as 1 bird?
うさぎって、1羽っていうのかな？
Do you say 1 "wa" for a rabbit?
1羽と言うのかしらね。
I wonder if you say 1 "wa".
え、本当にそれでいいの？
Eh, is that really okay?
じゃあちょっと真ん中をすばるにして、じゃあ真ん中のレバーを引きます。
Then let's make the center Subaru, and pull the center lever.
お願いします！で、ぼたんちゃんをお湯に。え？
Please! And, Botan-chan to hot water. Eh?
ぼたんちゃんのレバーも引く。でもこれ
Pull Botan-chan's lever too. But if this...
これだったら当てはまる。だってこの裏シオンちゃんだから、どっちの動物でもシオンちゃん動物じゃないから。
If it's this, it fits. Because the back is Shion-chan, and neither animal is Shion-chan.
いやでも、でもシオン様は魔女っ子だから何でも慣れちゃう気がするな。
But Shion-sama is a magical girl so she can get used to anything, I feel.
な、な、そんなこと言われたらこまちゃんよ、そんなこと
If you say that, Koma-chan, like that--
え？どうこれ？え？どう？
Eh? How is this? Eh? How?
いや、すばるは公式としてわと読むのか、にん、と読むのかに揺らぎがするけど、まあでもすばるは多分アヒルだから…どうなのこれ…アヒルだから！
Subaru as an official has a fluctuation whether to read it as "wa" or "nin", but she's a duck!
はい！バナナさん！
Yes! Banana-san!
本当にいいの？帰れないかもしれないよ？え？やだ！
Is that really okay? We might not be able to go back! Eh? No way!
このあとみんなのところに帰れなくなっちゃうかもしれない。
After this, we might not be able to go back to everyone's places.
やばい、めちゃ熱かけられてんだけど！ねえ、やだやだ！ねえ！
Oh no, we're being heated up so much! Hey, no way, no way!
みんな誰か助けて！帰れないよ！
Everyone, someone help! We can't go back!
やばい！やばい熱い！
Oh no! Oh no, it's hot!
ちょっと待って、や、でも…２羽、1匹？え、これ、2羽と1匹。
Wait a minute, no, but... 2 birds, 1 beast? Eh, 2 birds and 1 beast.
だから、多分ウサギを「羽」と呼ぶんだよ、現代日本語では。
So, they probably call rabbits "wa" in modern Japan.
なるほどね？そうそうそうそう。
I see? Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
どうだ！バナナさん！
How's that! Banana-san!
くっそ熱いでーーす！
It's freaking hooot!
やったーー！
Yaaay!
え、ウサギって「羽」って読むんだ。
Eh, rabbits are read as "wa".
そう、ウサギは「羽」って読むんだ。
Right, rabbits are read as "wa".
話なんすよ。
That's how it is.
そうなんだ！絶対頭わかんないと思ったもんこの問題！消去法だったかも。
Is that so! I thought my brain wouldn't get this puzzle! Process of elimination.
シオンちゃんが、その人間だから違うかなっていう消去法だった、正直。
Honestly, it was process of elimination, thinking Shion-chan is human.
なるほどね。えじゃあ、もしシオン様がコロン様とかだったら迷ってた
I see. Eh then, if Shion-sama was Korone-sama or someone, I'd have been lost--
いや、もうわかんないから、わかんなかった。お湯が逆かなって思ってた。
No, I didn't get it anymore. I thought maybe Hot Water was the opposite.
よっしゃーー！
All right!
消去法だよね、完全に。うわ、これ
It was process of elimination completely. Woah, this...
絵は、ちょっと
The drawing is a bit...
今度からは写真入れてこっ
Next time, let's include photos!
やった！
Yay!
やった！やった！やった！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
じゃあ、さきほど数字に書かれてたのは何番でしたか？
So, what number was written on the numbers just now?
え？
Eh?
7？
7?
あれ、覚えてない？もしかして
Huh, you don't remember? Could it be?
あ、やべ、何番だっけ？
Ah, crap, what number was it?
や、やったーー！うわぁー！
Yay—! Wooah!
待って待って、あれってこれを分かんないと脱出できないでしょ？
Wait, wait, if you don't figure this out, you can't escape, right?
えーっと、なんだっけ？ 73、73、73？
Um, what was it? 73, 73, 73?
いや、インテリがセールスあればね、覚えられるもんねぇ。なんだっけなんだっけ
Well, if you have high intelligence/sales, you can remember it, right? What was it, what was it?
え？わかんない。え、ねねちゃんが解いたの覚えて。え、知りたいちょこちゃん知りたいです。
Eh? I don't know. Eh, I remember Nene-chan solving it. Eh, I want to know, Choko-chan, I want to know.
え、じゃあ、かわいくちょこにおねだりしてくれないと教えてあげられないかも。
Eh, then, if you don't cutely beg Choko, I might not tell you.
445開けて、445かわいいおねだり聞きたいな、ちょこ。
Open 445, 445, I want to hear a cute beg, Choko.
あ、1、あ、8、9、10、20、80、あ、わかんなくちゃった。あ、分かんないね、あ、分かんないね。
Ah, 1, ah, 8, 9, 10, 20, 80, ah, I don't get it anymore. Ah, I don't get it, ah, I don't get it.
お願いします。お願いします。お願いします。お願いしま…耳元聞きてぇって。
Please. Please. Please. Please... "I want to hear it close to my ear," they say.
やっぱみんなのことも大好きだから教えてほしいな。ね、言ってよ！地獄で土下座してくんねえだもん、もう一回だ！
As expected, I love everyone too, so I want you to tell me. Hey, say it! You won't dogeza in hell, so do it again!
やだ、うんこちゃんお願いしま…うるさい、44でmやめろ！
No way, Unko-chan, please... Shut up, stop at 44!
お願いします。お願いします。45ってわかんないんだわ。
Please. Please. I don't know 45.
お願いします。おねがいします。おねがいします。みんなのこと大好きだから、
Please. Please. Please. Because I love everyone,
アクアに教えてほしいな。きゅるんってしてほしい。みんなのこと大好きだから、あくあ教えてほしいな。
I want Aqua to tell me. I want you to do a "kyurun" pose. Because I love everyone, Aqua, I want you to tell me.
教えてほしいな。アクア教えてほしいな。お願いしま…教えて…！
I want you to tell me. Aqua, I want you to tell me. Please... tell me...!
しょうがないわね、もう。
It can't be helped, jeez.
じゃあ、正解は 731 です。
Well then, the correct answer is 731.
なさち、なさち、なさち、なさち、なさち。
Nasachi, nasachi, nasachi, nasachi, nasachi.
なさち！
Nasachi!
あ、入った！あ、入った！
Ah, it went in! Ah, it went in!
赤様、一緒に連れてってくれるんですよね。
Akasama, you're taking me along with you, right?
よーし、なめぞう。
Alright, Namezou.
あれ、聞いてる赤様？赤様？ああ！
Huh, are you listening, Akasama? Akasama? Ahh!
ステージの帰り道、覚えました！
I remembered the way back from the stage!
赤様、聞いてます？ちょこの話。
Akasama, are you listening? Choko's story.
一緒に連れてってくれるの？ねえ、待っててね！
You're taking me with you? Hey, wait for me!
赤様！ちょっと、ちょこも出して！
Akasama! Wait, let Choko out too!
ワン、ツー、サン、シ！
One, two, three, four!
まず朝起きたら チェック・ザ・通知
First thing when I wake up in the morning, check the notifications
軽々未来コミュニケーション ＼ハーイ！／
Easily future communication, \Okaay!/
小粋なジョークで ダンス・ザ・通信
With a smart joke, dance the communication
フロアを沸かせ オヤユビで ＼ハーイ！／
Excite the floor with my thumb, \Okaay!/
そろそろ時間だ 外に出なきゃ…
It's about time, I have to go outside...
通るのはもちろん裏通り ＼ハーイ！／
Of course, going through the back street, \Okaay!/
誰にも会わずにゴールインのはずが
Without meeting anybody, I'm supposed to reach my goal, but
まさかの気になるあの人が…
Unexpectedly, that person I care about...
＼おはよう！／
\Good morning!/
「えぁ!?エトアノ…ナンダコニコ、イルノ、デスカ!?アノ今日 ソノオ…」
"Huh!? Wh-um... Whatareyoudoinghere!? Err, today that's..."
＼どうしたの！／
\What's wrong?/
「イヤ…イエアノ、チョト…ドゥフwイヤ！アノ、エ、エ!?…」
"No... Y-yeah, um, just... dufuw yeah! Um, e, eh!?..."
「うわぁあああああ！」
"Uwaaaaaah!"
デ、デ、ディスコミュニケーション
D-d-dis-communication
あなたと電波交信
Wireless contact with you
まるでできない 言葉が出ない
I can't quite do it, words don't come out
ちゅ、ちゅ、宙に舞い出しちゃうくらい
Like fluttering in the air
フィーリングで通じ合いたい
With that feeling, I want to communicate
マジでできない 伝わりゃしない
I really can't do it, it isn't conveyed
ああ！
Ahh!
星の数の言葉の中から
From words as numerous as the stars
ひとつ何かを探してる
Which one am I looking for
伝えたいのに しかし、あたしは ディスコミュニケーションだ！だ！だ！
I want to convey it, but I'm a discommunication alien, yes! I! Am!
フー
Foo
1・2・3・4・5・6・7・8
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8
アドレナリンからまわりだったり
Spinning round from adrenaline
それでも笑顔できゅるきゅるりん
Still, with a smile, kyurukyururin
プリンセスでいいんです
I'm fine with being a princess
それしか似合わないんです
Anything other than that doesn't suit me
目をみずしてばみんな一こう（いちころ）
After looking at their eyes, everyone's one-hit ko
そういうお年頃
Or around that age
かわいい！
\You're cute!/
「え！きゅんにみんなどうしたのありがとう」
"Wha! What's up with you all of a sudden! Thank you-"
「いや、そんなこと言われても照れるというかなんというか」
"No, even if you say that, I feel shy or brave or something (lol)"
＼愛してる！／
\We love you!/
「えっ！？いや困ったな、ありがとううれしいな、わたしもう…」
"Wha!? Oh no~ I'm in trouble (lol), thank you, I'm so happy, me too..."
あ、ゆめか？
Oh, it was a dream.
デ、デ、ディスコミュニケーション
D-d-dis-communication
あなたの感情予想
Predicting your feelings
1, 2, 3, 4
まず朝起きたらチェック ザ 通知
First thing in the morning, check notifications,
軽々 未来コミュニケーション
Effortless future communication,
（＼おっきー！／）
(Great!)
小粋なジョークで ダンス ザ 通信
With a witty joke, dance the transmission,
フロアを沸かせ オヤユビで
Rock the floor with a flick of your thumb,
（＼おっきー！／）
(Great!)
そろそろ時間だ 外に出なきゃ
It's almost time, I gotta go outside,
通るのは もちろん裏通り
Of course, taking the backstreets.
（＼おっきー！／）
(Great!)
誰にも合わず ゴールインのはずが
I should've made it without seeing anyone, but
まさかの 気になるあの人が
Suddenly, that person I care about—
「おはよー！」
"Good morning!"
「え！急にみ…え、とあの…なんでここに、いるんですか…!?あのきょうそのお…」
"Eh? Suddenly— um, ugh... why are you here...!? Uh, today, um..."
「どうしたの？」
"What's wrong?"
「いや…いけあの、ちょ…どふ、いや、あの、え、え…？」
"N-No! I mean, uh, j-just— ugh, no, um, e-eh...?"
「うわーーーっ！」
"Aaaaaah!"
ディ・ディ・ディスコミュニケーション
Dis-dis-discommunication!
あなたと電波交信
Communicating with you via radio waves,
まるですべきない 言葉が出ない
It's like I can't do it, the words won't come out.
ちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅに舞い絶っちゃうくらい
So much so that I'm dancing into the kiss,
フィーリングで通じ合いたい
I want us to connect through feelings.
マジでできない 伝わりやしない
I really can't do it, it just won't get across.
ああ！
Ah!
星の数の言葉の中から
Out of a galaxy of words,
ひとつ何かを探してる
I'm searching for just one.
伝えたいのに しかし あたしは
I want to convey it, but I'm an
ディスコミュ星人 だ・だ・だ！
Discommunication alien, da-da-da!
フー！
Whoo!
マイワールドならマイカーストで 思い通り (いえい！)
In my own world, with my own custom, just as planned (Yeah!)
先手必勝 in the good show みたいな
Like preemptive victory in the good show,
絶対負けない メゲないショゲない 弱音はないわ
Never losing, never giving up, no weak words.
スポットライトで キラキラ輝く
Sparkling and shining brightly in the spotlight,
キラッとライクな あたし☆
A sparkling-like me☆
あー、1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8
Ah, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8
アドレナリン 空回りだったり
Adrenaline spinning out of control,
それでも笑顔で キュラキュレルリン
Still smiling dazzlingly,
プリンセスでいいんです それしか似合わないんです
A princess is fine, it's the only thing that suits me.
目をみきしちゃえばみんなイチコロ
If I look them in the eye, everyone's won over,
そういうお年頃
That's how old I am.
「かわいい！」
"So cute!"
「え！急にみんなどうしたの！あ、ありがとう…！」
"Eh? Why is everyone acting so sudden! Ah, thank you...!"
「いやぁ、そんなこと言われても照れるというか何というか…」
"Jeez, being told that makes me feel shy or whatever..."
「愛してる！」
"We love you!"
「えっ！？いや～困ったな」
"Eh!? Man, I'm in trouble!"
「ありがとう嬉しいなああたしも…」
"Thank you, I'm so happy, me too..."
あ、夢か。
Ah, it was a dream.
ディ・ディ・ディスコミュニケーション
Dis-dis-discommunication!
あなたの感情予報
Your emotional forecast,
まるでできない 答えが出ない
It's like I can't do it, no answer comes out.
ちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅじゃ足りないくらい
So much so that kisses aren't enough,
フィーリングで感じ合って そのまま溶けて…とか
Feeling each other and melting away...
そんな妄想中
Such delusions in progress.
ディ・ディ・ディスコミュニケーション
Dis-dis-discommunication!
解答霊的ナレーション
An answer-like spiritual narration,
ガチでできない 伝わりやしない
I really can't do it, it won't get across.
ああ！
Ah!
夢の中ならうまくできるの
I can do it well in my dreams,
だけどリアルじゃできやしない
But I can't do it in reality.
伝えたいほど キョドる心は
The more I want to convey, the more my heart panics,
同じ言語じゃないみたい
As if we don't speak the same language.
なら！
Then!
星の数の言葉は捨てるよ
I'll throw away a galaxy of words,
気持ちはほら、ここにあるよ
Look, my feelings are right here.
伝えてみるさ だって あたしは
I'll try to convey them, because I'm an
ディスコミュ星人 だ・だ・だ・だ…
Discommunication alien, da-da-da-da...
あ、なんでもないです。
Ah, it's nothing.
あ…
Ah...
皆さんどうもこんにちは！湊あくあです。この度湊あくあのソロライブが開催決定！
Hello everyone! I'm Minato Aqua. My 2nd solo live has been officially decided!
あくあ色のすーぱーどりーむから1年半、みんなとの約束、守りに来たよ！
It's been 1.5 years since Aqua-iro Super Dream, and I've come to keep my promise to you all!
2022年1月28日、豊洲PITにて開催！現地来場チケットの1次先行＆SPWNでの配信チケット発売開始！
Taking place on January 28, 2022 at Toyosu PIT! Venue ticket 1st pre-order & SPWN streaming tickets are on sale!
へんてこな衣装のNEKOに導かれて銀河のアイドルメイドが『わんだ～らんど♪』にいざなう！？湊あくあ初の有観客ライブ！！
Guided by a quirky costume's NEKO, the galaxy's idol maid invites you to 'Wonderland♪'!? Minato Aqua's first live with an audience!!
今年もみんなと会えるの楽しみだな！
I'm so excited to see everyone this year too!
みなとあくあ ワンマンライブ 2022 あくあ色inわんだ～らんど♪
Minato Aqua One-Man Live 2022: Aqua-iro in Wonderland♪
2022年も『あくあ色』が止まらない！！あくあクルーとともにまだまだ見ぬ新しい世界へ！
In 2022, 'Aqua-iro' won't stop!! Heading into a brand new world with Aqua Crew!
ねえ、来いしょ！ねえってばー！
Hey, listen! Hey, I said listen!
なんだんだんだ…！と、いうことで、みなさん！
What, what, what...! And so, everyone!
重大発表、見てくれましたかー？
Did you watch the major announcement?
ということで、なんと！湊あくあ、ソロライブが決定しましたーーー！
And so, unbelievably! Minato Aqua's solo live has been decided!
みなとあくあ ワンマンライブ 2022 あくあ色inわんだ～らんど♪
Minato Aqua One-Man Live 2022: Aqua-iro in Wonderland♪
え、2022年の8月にね、えっとファーストワンマンをやらせていただいて
Um, in August 2022— I mean, we did our first one-man live,
来年もできたらいいねなんて話をしていたんですけれどもね、いろんな事情もあって…
And we talked about hopefully doing it next year too, but due to various circumstances...
え、来年1月の28日に、え、なんとワンマンライブをやらせていただくことになりました！ありがとうみんなー！
Um, on January 28 next year, um, we'll be holding a one-man live! Thank you everyone!
ということで、今回、がぉー先生にキービジュアルを描いてもらいました！
And so this time, Gao-sensei drew the key visual for us!
去年がぉー先生がTwitterで「おっぱいのひらしくて」って書いて…！
Last year Gao-sensei tweeted something like 'her boobs look like...'!
おい！許ぜんな！私のちょっと、ちょっと濁せたクセに重大発表ありますよ、みたいなことツイートしてて許ぜんな！
Hey! Give me a break! Tweeting something vague like 'there's a major announcement coming', seriously!
いや、いつもありがとうございます！可愛い絵を描いてくださってまして今回も…
Well, thank you as always! Drawing such cute art, and this time too...
見てくださました。可愛、めちゃくちゃ可愛くない？
Please take a look. Isn't it super cute,
正直。ヤバいよね。めっちゃ可愛い。
honestly? It's amazing. Super cute.
そして、ライブのロゴはコミワークスの島田美里さんに作っていただきました。ありがとうございます！
And the live logo was created by Midori Shimada of COMIC WORKS. Thank you so much!
すごい可愛い！おしゃれなロゴね作っていただきまして、
It's so cute! She made such a stylish logo for us,
そして、え、キービジュアルの猫、猫、猫にもね衣装が今回ねあります。
and for the key visual, the cat, cat, cat also has a new outfit this time.
なんかいつの間にかさ、隣にいるんだけど猫、おかしくない？
Somehow, before I knew it, it's right next to me, but cat, isn't that weird?
去年私がこうやってやってたのにさ、今日さ、ここにいたら猫がいるんだけど。
Last year I was doing this, but today, a cat is just standing right here.
え？なんかね、当たり前みたいになってる。ね？
Huh? Somehow, it's become completely normal. Right?
ということで、キービジュアルの猫の一生ゲハンは鮫太先生です。
So, the key visual cat's outfit designer is Sameta-sensei.
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
ということで、ちょっとね、あの詳細などをちょっと詳しく見ていきたいんですけども、
So, let's take a closer look at the details.
来年2022年の1月28日金曜日より、え、豊洲PITで行われることになりまして配信チケットももちろんあります。
Next year, on Friday, January 28, 2022, it will be held at Toyosu PIT, and streaming tickets are available, of course!
でね、一今年は実さは、あの、まあ本当は現地でやる予定、まああったかなかったか、あれなんですけども、
And you know, the year before last, we were actually planning to do it in person—well, whether we were or not—
ま、オンラインライブで、なんとね、あの、そう、やりた、本当やりたかったんだけどオンラインライブになってしまったという感じだったんですが、
Anyway, it ended up being an online live, and... we really wanted an in-person show, but it turned into an online live.
今年は、来年か、来年はついに私実わ初めてなんです。
This year—next year, I mean. Next year, finally, it's actually my first time.
初めての、え、現地ありでの、え、ソロライブをさせていただくことになりました。ありがとうございます！
I'm going to have my very first solo live with an in-person audience! Thank you so much!
いやマジで嬉しい！
I'm honestly so happy!
ずっとね、やっぱその、なんだろうライブやりたいて言ってたので、そうできてね本当に嬉しいです。
I've always said I wanted to do a live concert, so I'm really happy we could make it happen.
そしてね場所は豊洲PIT。一番初めの、えっとホロライブの、えっとライブ、全体ライブが、たしか豊洲PITだったかな？
And the venue is Toyosu PIT. The very first Hololive overall live was at Toyosu PIT, if I remember correctly.
で、今回はねやらせていただくことになりました。なんかすごく思い出深い地ではありますけれどもよろしくお願いします。
And now we get to perform there. It's a place full of memories, so I'm looking forward to it!
そして、え、会場、会場の、会場会場ってなんかすごい変な感じだね。
And the venue opening—saying "venue, venue" sounds really weird.
会場の、え、会場時間は17時。そして配信の会場は17時半。そして開演は18時です！
The doors open at 17:00, the stream starts at 17:30, and the show begins at 18:00!
わあ！配信はSPWNで行われます。
Wow! The stream will be hosted on SPWN.
え、公演放送後のアーカイブは、え、2022年の、え、2月の28日まで何度でも見放題ができます。とってもお得です！お得なんです！
The archive after the show can be watched as many times as you want until February 28, 2022. It's an amazing deal! Such a bargain!
え、チケット購入は2022年2月28日まで可能です。みんな買ってね。
Ticket purchases are available until February 28, 2022. Everyone go buy yours!
去年はねちょっと、あのサイトが落ちてね、あのヤバイみたいなことがあったんですけど、今年は大丈夫。
Last year the site crashed and things got pretty crazy, but this year is going to be fine.
万全を期しているので、今年こそは、え、チケットページ落としません。落させません。
We're taking every precaution, so this year we definitely won't let the ticket page crash. We won't allow it.
みなとあくあはいつもね破戒神と言われているんですが、今回は絶対にサイトは落とさない。
Minato Aqua is always called the "God of Destruction," but this time I won't let the site crash.
今回気合を入れてますので皆さんも気合を入れてチケット戦争に望んでください。お願いします。
I'm putting all my energy into it, so everyone please gear up and win those tickets! Please!
そして、え、デジタルフラスタというのもあって、え、ま今回ね、あのコロナウイルス感染予防の観点から当日フラワースタンドやプレゼント、おてがみをを受け取ることがなんとできないんです。ごめんなさい。あー、ごめんね。
Also, we have digital flower stands. Due to COVID-19 infection prevention measures, we unfortunately won't be able to accept physical flower stands, gifts, or letters on the day of the event. I'm so sorry. Ah, I'm sorry!
その代わりにデジタルフラワースタンドっていうのを、え、送ってもらうことができます。こちらの申込締め切りなどは、特設ホームページ、デジタルフラワースタンド特設サイトのスパンはチェックしてください。
Instead, you can send a digital flower stand. Please check the special website for application deadlines and details!
そしてここからはみなとあくあ重大発表ではなく、え公演ハッシュタグというのがございましてみなとあくあソロライブです。
And from here on, rather than a Minato Aqua major announcement, we have a concert hashtag, which is "Minato Aqua Solo Live".
なので、えライブの応援はみなとあくあソロライブでたくさん呟いてくれると嬉しいんです。今からでもねたくさん呟いちゃってください。
So I'd be really happy if you tweet a lot to support the live. You can start tweeting right away!
ジラッぷでもねよかったらっぱい呟いてください。お願います。みんなのね反応ね後で見るからね。
Even if it's just a short post, please tweet away! Please! I'll check everyone's reactions later!
さらに、ライブのグッズを紹介します。えライブにマストで必要なTシャツ、ライト、タオルがセットになったワンダセットをね、
Next, let's introduce the live merchandise! We have the "Wonder Set," which includes the essential T-shirt, light, and towel for the live.
あのさワンダーランド、インワンダーランドってさ可愛いでしょう？ダサいとか言わないね。アクリルインワンダーランドワンダーランドだかね、音符だからみんな頼むよ！
"In Wonderland, Wonderland"—isn't that cute? Don't call it uncool! Acrylic In Wonderland Wonderland, you know, with musical notes, so everyone please order it!
はい、ということでね、えーとワンダセットの特典として、今回のライブのパンフレットと私からの手紙がついて、おおい、なんだこれ？
Yes, so, as a bonus for the Wonder Set, it comes with the live pamphlet and a letter from me—wait, what's this?
ね、台本にさ私じゃなくてアティシって書いてあるんだけど。ね？どういうこと？ね？台本にアティシって書いてあるんだけどおかしいだろこれ。おい、誰が書いたんだこの台本。
Hey, the script says "Atishi" instead of "Watashi." Huh? What is this? Hey, it literally says "Atishi" in the script, that's weird! Hey, who wrote this script?!
え、ワンダセットは、在庫が
Um, for the Wonder Set, stock is—
なくなり次第終了となりますので、
Sales will end as soon as they run out,
ぜひお気をつけて買ってね。
so please be sure to buy them!
ほらイモンジュんだよ。
Look, it's Holimon.
手紙はねワンダーセットにしかつきません。
The letter only comes with the Wonder Set.
なんて書いてあるかは
What it says is...
これを買った人の楽しみです。
something for the purchaser to look forward to!
次は後日発送のグッズです。
Next are the goods shipped at a later date.
こちら！
Here they are!
アクリルスタンドやアクキー、
We have acrylic stands, keychains,
タペストリー、缶バッジセット、カラトリーセットなどもご用意しました。
tapestries, badge and cutlery sets ready.
これアクリルスタンドとね、これキーホルダーですけれども、
These are the acrylic stand and keychain...
かわいい！かわいいなこれ、えー？
So cute! Aren't they adorable? Huh?
そしてねもう一個ね、え、カラトリーセットなども、
And another one, the cutlery set
え、グッズにかな？
and other goods...
グッズのところにこちらタペストリー、
in the goods section, we have the tapestry,
缶バッジセット、カラトリーセットと
badge set, and cutlery set.
やば！
Whoa!
え、これね、このカラトリーセットスプーンどこにね、
Look, this cutlery set spoon... there's a cat
猫ついてるのやばくない？猫。
on it, isn't that crazy? A cat!
猫
A cat!
猫ついてるのめちゃかわいいでしょ、これ。
Having a cat on it is super cute, right?
とゆことで、どのグッズもめちゃめちゃ可愛いので、
So, since all the goods are super cute,
グッズの注文詳細、注意事項は各ショップのページや
please check the order details and notes
特設ホームページのグッズページの追記をチェックしてください。
on each shop's page or the special homepage!
全部ね、え、概要欄とかにね、
Everything has been updated
え、なんとね更新されておりますから、
in the description box, so...
はい、よかったらぜひ皆さんね、え、購入してみてはいかがでしょうか。そして
yeah, if you'd like, why not try purchasing some? And...
チケットもねなんと、もう今から発売なのかな？
tickets are also on sale starting right now?
そうです、買えちゃいます！
That's right, you can buy them!
グッズも今から買えちゃうのかな？
Can you buy the goods right now too?
ということで、みんなね概要欄から
So everyone, hurry and check
急いでチェックチェックチェックチェック！
the description box!
はい、ということでねみんなねよかったら、
Alright, so if you'd like, everyone,
え、2022年アクア色インワンダーランド
please look forward to...
楽しみにしててねー！
Aqua-iro in Wonderland 2022!
なんと10時からです！
It starts at 10:00!
10時からだって、みんな。10時から。
It starts at 10:00, everyone.
10時から開始らしいわ、みんな。
At 10:00. It starts at 10:00, guys.
10時から、オッケー？みんな、間違えたわ。
10:00, okay? Wait, I made a mistake.
間違えてた。グッズ22時でした！
I was wrong. The goods are at 22:00!
すみませんでしたー！
I'm so sorry!
22時からね、これ終わったらみんなね、まだあるから。
From 22:00, after this, there's still more.
まだあるから。
There's still more.
え、告知タイムだと思ったでしょ？ちゃうから。
You thought it was the announcement time? Nope.
ちゃんと私最後までやり切るから、この重大発表ライブ。ちゃんとね最後まで見てててください。
I'm going to see this major announcement through!
えー、そしてね、ま、さっき見てもらった映像で
And, earlier in the video you watched,
みんながね知らない曲がたぶん流れてたよね。
there was a song playing you probably didn't know.
え、みんな聞いてた？「きらきら未来」
Did you guys listen? "Kira Kira Mirai",
みんな聞いてた？
did you listen?
あれ、「この曲知らねえな」って思った人ね、たくさんいると思うんですけども、
I think many thought, "I don't know this song,"
えー、今日この重大発表を楽しみにしてくれてたみんなのために
but today, for everyone who looked forward to this,
新曲を歌っちゃいますー！
I'm going to sing a new song!
ということで、なんとですね、この曲はあのね、私ね、あの「パンパイヤ」とか、
So, actually, I've covered songs
えっと「シンデレラ」とかね、歌ってみた揚げさせていただいてますけど、
like "Vampire" and "Cinderella",
DECO*27さんが作ってくださった楽曲で、
and this is a song created by DECO*27-san.
もうすごい豪華すぎる、いいんですか？
It's so luxurious, is this really okay?!
そして、え、今日の24時からダウンロード&ストリーミングが、え、配信開始となりますので、
Also, starting at 24:00 today, streaming starts,
そちらもよろしくお願いします。チェックしてね！
so please check that out too! Check it!
一足先にね、ライブでは聴けますが、もう一回聴きたいって人はねよかったら、えっと、
You can hear it early at the live, but if you want
いろんなねストリーミングサイト、いっぱいますので、そちらで、え、ダウンロードストリーミング聴いてみてください！
to listen again, check out various streaming sites!
そして来年1月28日のワンマンに向けて、
And heading toward the solo live on January 28,
この後も続々と
from now on, one after another...
これだけじゃなく他にも新曲を制作していて、
we're producing other new songs, and they'll
え、次々と発表されていくので
be announced one after another,
楽しみに待っててね！マジでねいい曲ばっかだから、
so please look forward to it! Seriously,
マジでやばいです。マジでやばいです。正直言います、マジでやばいです。
all the songs are amazing, seriously amazing.
ということで、今日はねみんなね遊びに来てくれて
So everyone, thank you so much
本当にありがとう！
for coming to hang out today!
じゃあ、早速新曲を歌おうかなと思うんですけど、
Well then, I thought I'd sing the new song
いいですか？みんなねまだ名前も知らないからね、あの曲のね。
right away, is that okay? You don't know the title yet.
じゃあね、今回はね、フリもありで
So this time, I'm planning to sing it
歌っていこうと思っておりますのでよろしくお願いします！
with choreography too, so please look forward to it!
ということで、今日は見に来てくれて本当にありがとう！
So, thank you so much for coming today!
ライブよかったら楽しみにしててね！それでは聴いてください。
Please look forward to the live! Now, listen.
キラキラ
Kira Kira
今日のおはよう
Good morning today,
少しどきどきするな
I'm feeling a little nervous.
選ばれるかって
Wondering if I'll be chosen,
不安になって ああ
feeling anxious, ah...
だめなところ ばかりで
It makes me sick
いやになりなア
seeing only my flaws.
進んでみたって
Even when I push forward,
うまくいかない けど
things don't go well, but...
今日のおはよう
Good morning today,
少しどきどきするなァ
I'm a little nervous.
選ばれるかって不安になってァ
Anxious about whether I'll be chosen,
だめなところばかりで嫌になるなァ
Sick of all my flaws.
進んでみたってうまくいかないけど
I tried moving forward, but it didn't go well,
またも “大失敗” はお腹いっぱい
And I'm already full of "major failures".
変わりたくて振り絞ったんだ
Because I wanted to change, I mustered my courage,
描いた未来を好きになりたいから
To learn to love the future I drew,
きらきらっと輝こうか
Shall I sparkle and shine?
間違えちゃっても大丈夫
It's okay even if I make mistakes,
できないことができるようになるよ
I'll become able to do what I couldn't.
先は長いから
The road ahead is long,
疲れちゃったら止めろこうか
So if you get tired, let's take a break,
少し眠ったら元通り
And sleep a bit to get back to normal.
したいことしたいようにさ
To do what I want, the way I want.
わがままだしじゃないでしょ？
That's not being selfish, right?
忘れないよこの想いは
I won't forget this feeling,
重ねてもっと届くように
So it can reach further as it builds up.
変えられるんだ変えていくんだ
I can change it, I'm going to change it.
きらきらしたいから
Because I want to sparkle!
なになに
Na na na...
昨日の「おはよう」
Yesterday's "Good morning",
振り返る今日のあたしは
Looking back, today I am
ほんのちょこっとだって
Just a tiny bit
強くなれたみたい
Feeling like I've grown stronger.
笑い方もなんだか自然な感じだ
Even my smile feels somehow natural.
いつも通りでは
As always,
もっと進化していくみたい
It seems I'm evolving even more.
怖いよ実際だけどもう一回
It's scary, truly, but once more,
乾いたハート振り絞っていこう
Let's squeeze out our dry hearts and go!
なりたいあたしがオイデをするから
Because the me I want to be is calling out.
まだいけるよ
We can still keep going!
きらきらっと輝こうか
Shall we sparkle and shine?
間違えちゃっても大丈夫
It's okay even if we make mistakes.
できないことができるようになるよ
We'll become able to do what we couldn't.
先は長いから
The road ahead is long,
疲れちゃったら止めろこうか
So if you get tired, let's take a break,
少し眠ったら元通り
And sleep a bit to get back to normal.
したいことしたいようにさ
To do what I want, the way I want.
わがままだしじゃないでしょ？
That's not being selfish, right?
忘れないよこの想いは
I won't forget this feeling,
重ねてもっと届くように
So it can reach further as it builds up.
変えられるんだ変えていくんだ
I can change it, I'm going to change it.
きらきらしたいから
Because I want to sparkle!
なになに
Na na na...
消せない弱さ重ねる強さ
Weaknesses we can't erase, strengths we pile up,
ダメなあたしずっとずっと歌うよ
Even my useless self, I'll keep on singing.
輝けること変われちゃうこと
Being able to shine, being able to change,
ダメなあたしずっとずっと見ていてほしい
My imperfect self, I want you to keep watching.
重ねてもっと届くように
So it can reach further as it builds up.
変えられるんだ変えていくんだ
I can change it, I'm going to change it.
きらきらしたいから
Because I want to sparkle!
なになに
Na na na...
消せない弱さ重ねる強さ
Weaknesses we can't erase, strengths we pile up,
ダメなあたしずっとずっと歌うよ
Even my useless self, I'll keep on singing.
輝けること変われちゃうこと
Being able to shine, being able to change,
ダメなあたしずっとずっと見ていて
My imperfect self, I want you to keep watching...
みなさんどうもこんにちは！
Hello everyone!
湊あくあです！
I'm Minato Aqua!
この度、湊あくあのソロライブが
This time, Minato Aqua's solo live
開催決定！
has been officially decided!
「あくあ色すーぱー☆どりーむ♪」から1年半、
One and a half years since "Aqua Iro Super☆Dream♪",
みんなとの約束、守りに来たよ！
I've come to keep my promise to everyone!
2022年1月28日（金）豊洲PITにて開催予定！
Scheduled for Friday, January 28, 2022 at Toyosu PIT!
今年もみんなと会えるの楽しみだな～！
I'm so excited to meet everyone again this year!
湊あくあワンマンライブ2022「あくあ色 in わんだ～らんど♪」
Minato Aqua One-Man Live 2022 "Aqua Iro in Wonderland♪"
開催!!
is happening!!
今名前出さないって思った？ちょっと、ねえ、可愛いじゃん！ねえってば！
Did you think I wouldn't say my name just now? Come on, isn't that cute? Hey!